

# HAROLD JULIAN GARCIA CHAPARRO

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

# **PROFILE**

I am a web and mobile frontend developer passionate about the development of truly useful and enjoyable technological solutions for end users.

At a professional level I have great interest and knowledge focused on the development of web and mobile applications, focused on always offering a pleasant and attractive experience to end users who interact with the product.

Thus, the technical and structural knowledge provided by Systems and Computing Engineering, together with the aesthetic and experimental knowledge provided by Design, allow for truly innovate ideas to materialize

# CONTACT

**Phone**: +57 320 279 4866

**Email**: hj.garcia652@gmail.com

Github: https://www.github.com/dlorah01

Portfolio: https://losandes.ccnsite.com/dlorah01

Website: https://www.haroldgarcia.co

# **SKILLS & KNOWLEDGE**

# Programming:

HTML SQL CSS Node JS Git Express **Javascript** Gulp lava GraphQL MongoDB NgPrime Redux Sass Typescript Bootstrap RxIS Angular Angular Material Heroku Firebase **SCRUM** Data Structures

#### Design:

Adobe Illustrator Figma
Adobe Photoshop Design Thinking
Prototyping Mobile-First Approach
Adobe XD Desktop-First Approach
Prototyping

# **EDUCATION**

# UNIVERSIDAD DE LOS ANDES Computing and Systems Engineer

Completion: December 2016 - Graduation: March 2017 Bogotá, Colombia

# UNIVERSIDAD DE LOS ANDES Designer

Completion: July 2019 - Graduation: April 2020 Bogotá, Colombia

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **MEDICAL GLOBAL CENTER**

- www.medicalglobalcenter.com - Web/Mobile Developer and Designer January 2016 - June 2017

- Develop the new version of the company's website, redefine content to be used on the website, understand how the health sector works and how this affects the way information should be displayed.
- Create web components within the website, focused on managing and delivering the results of occupational medical exams virtually.
- Optimize the contents and images of the website, which improve the income of the company through the use of SEO tools and digital marketing.
- Develop a system for monitoring, control and optimization of operations performed in ambulances through the creation of a mobile application, Web server and API.

#### ON THE GARDEN

## - www.onthegarden.co -

Web/Mobile Developer and Designer July 2017 - December 2018

- Develop the company's website, edit photographs and icons to use on the website, understand how the gardening sector works and how it affects the way information should be displayed.
- Optimize texts and images of some views of the web page, so that the mobile version of the web page will be displayed correctly.
- Optimize the contents and images of the website, which improve the income of the company through the use of SEO tools and digital marketing.

## KNOWLEDGE AT PROCESSES AND TRAINING ALLIES

- www.kapta.biz -

Web/Mobile Developer August 2019 - October 2020

- Develop the new version of Automy website, having predefined all the views that compose it through wireframes.
- Restructure, provide technical support and create new components in the web application for internal use of time management of employees and scheduling training appointments in the automotive sector.
- Develop a system for displaying test results performed on the Classmarker platform through the creation of a web application, Web server and API.
- Propose options for displaying graphic elements in all of the projects and products of the company.

#### **PERSONAL SOFT**

#### - www.personalsoft.com -

Software Analyst October 2020 - June 2021

- Develop solutions for the correct treatment of vulnerabilities present in the different applications that are part of the Personas channel in Banistmo bank.
- Address requirements related to the improvement of the different applications that are part of the Personas channel in Banistmo bank.

#### **RABINOVICI & ASSOCIATES**

#### - www.rab2b.com -

Frontend Developer June 2021 - April 2022

- Develop fully functional responsive landing pages for clients, such as Zebra Technologies, Motorola Solutions, Donnelley Financial Solutions, Genesys and Hillrom; using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Gulp.
- Adjust and update previously created landing pages, following in detail the instructions provided by the client.
- Upload the landing pages so that they are visible on the web through the Eloqua (Oracle) platform, making sure it works correctly.
- Propose changes and updates for the renewal of the demonstration page of projects carried out for clients, following the guidelines and new corporate line established for the company.
- Implement proposed changes and updates to the demonstration page of projects carried out for clients, focused on optimizing the user experience.

#### **CAFETO SOFTWARE**

#### - www.cafetosoftware.com -

Frontend Developer May 2022 - Currently

- Migrate the current Demica client application, developed in Angular JS, using Angular 13.
- Develop using the component methodology, creating a library of completely reusable graphic components in projects.
- Develop under the monorepo approach, developing multiple projects in the same repository for the client.

## **PERSONAL WORK**

#### **MONITOR ME**

#### Alert system using Microsoft Band and OpenMTC

Systems and Computing Engineering thesis project December 2017

- Project focused on the approach of the Internet of Things (IoT) paradigm through technology.
- With the use of the OpenMTC platform, responsible for M2M communication, an using the Microsoft Band 2, a user follows biometric information through a mobile application made in Ionic 2, which are monitored and alerted to medical staff in real time.

# COLOR.SOUND() Look listening

Design thesis project December 2018

- Project focused on the use of available and accesible technology to improve the quality of life of people with visual disabilities.
- With the development of a mobile application, made in Ionic 3 for Android operating systems, aimed at people with visual impair mentsuch as blindness, it is sought to generate a sound resulting from the colors present in his envitonment, using common sensors in mobile devices such as the camera, as an alternative for a real perception of this visual signal.

# **LANGUAGES**

#### **SPANISH**

Native Language

#### **ENGLISH**

Advanced Language - B2+

#### FRENCH

Basic Language - A1

## REFERENCES

#### KAREM TATIANA GARCIA

Designer and Master in Marketing 311 447 2906

#### **JUAN SEBASTIAN VARGAS**

Computing and Systems Engineer and Master in Security 304 348 4523

#### JUAN JOSE RODRIGUEZ

Computing and Systems Engineer 313 282 8108

#### **JORGE MARIN**

Computing and Systems Engineer 321 514 6371

#### **DANIEL VALENZUELA**

Media Engineer 301 437 4388